# Dragos-Paul Marinescu

# Full-Stack Engineer

Bucharest, RO

✓ https://dragosmarinescu.codes✓ drmarinescu@icloud.com✓ bamtheboozle✓ bamtheboozle✓ in dragospaul95

I'm a Full-Stack Engineer with React / React Native with a strong desire to produce high quality software by constantly learning and applying current best practices in front-end/back-end development.

My main focus is on the front-end, **specializing on creating performant**, **optimized**, **and beautiful webapps**. I am an extremely product-focused developer who prioritizes collaboration, performance and user experience.

In my spare time, I play around with ML models and crypto/blockchain products.

SKILLS				
Frontend	Backend	Mok	oile	
Master	Advanced	Interi	mediate	
react react hooks typescript	nodejs serverless	mongodb	t native electron	ionic
javascript react query redux	sql / nosql			
graphql jest enzyme				
mediarecorder / screencapture api				
design systems figma / sketch				
scss styled components				
Other				
git github actions docker				
jenkins webpack yarn node				
WORK EXPERIENCE (6)				

# Full-Stack Engineer at Veed February 2022- August 2022

♦ https://veed.io/

Built an industry-leading web-based screen recorder from the ground up.

Functionality includes recording multiple streams individually (screen, slides, camera, audio), manipulating the streams, multiple scenes recording and integrating them within Veed's web-based editor.

- React
- Node.js
- Redux
- Typescript
- Canvas
- MediaRecorder API
- Chrome Extension

# Front-End Engineer at Arive GmbH July 2021- November 2021

♦ https://getarive.com

Arive is a start-up looking to deliver your favourite brands in under 30 minutes.

At Arive, I have joined as a Front-End Engineer and during the 4 month contract I helped them design, architect and bootstrap the content management platform using React. I collaborated with product and design teams in order to create an efficient, fast and scalable platform.

In addition to that, I have also mentored their existing team of front-end developers and took lead on implementing the features - this includes code reviews, sprint planning, story assignments, as well as general help when implementing/debugging code.

- React
- React Query
- Typescript
- Sentry
- SCSS

### React / React Native Developer at Innio Group June 2020- June 2021

https://www.innio.com

**Innio** is one of the top manufacturers of gas engines in the market. In order to digitalize their business, I helped them build an IoT application for the management of their engines and technicians across the world.

For the **engines**, some of the features include **tracking engine performance**, **monitoring and updating functioning parameters**, **triggering and resolving alerts**.

For the technicians, features I have built include multi-device sync, offline capabilities, conflict handling on form inputs, tracking time entries and expenses, report preview and generation.

- React
- React Query
- React Native
- Typescript
- Electron
- SCSS

# Front-End Tech Lead at Aera Technology May 2019- June 2020

♦ https://www.aeratechnology.com/

Aera is building a cognitive platform capable of understanding, recommending, predicting, and autonomously executing decisions to improve your business' supply chain management solution.

As Front-end Lead, I have started one of the company's backbone projects within the Aera Platform and implemented the architecture for it. I have mentored the junior and mid level developers across Romania, US, and Pakistan. I have also set up the CI/CD pipeline and Sonarqube in order to increase code quality.

The web-app allowed users to create skills and integrate them within Aera's data types, while also creating advanced schematics and data warehouse solutions.

- React
- Redux
- Typescript
- Webpack
- SCSS

# Front-End Engineer at Deloitte Digital January 2018- May 2019

https://www.deloittedigital.com/

Deloitte Digital builds and delivers end-to-end projects for client's business.

As Front-end Engineer at Deloitte, I have helped define the architecture of a digital transformation project for Prudential, one of UK's largest financial institutions.

The digital suite of secure web applications was designed with React & Redux & Typescript, following a micro-frontends approach that allowed greater productivity and less conflicts when developing, as each feature team was responsible for one micro-frontend. The apps were then coupled using Lerna and shipped as a standalone app that allowed consultants to create and manage pension schemes, clients and applications.

In the Bucharest office, I have also acted as Front-End Lead across the four feature teams, by taking architectural decisions, code reviewing, and by mentoring junior and mid-level developers write clean, testable and scalable code.

Moreover, I was actively involved in Deloitte's recruitment process and have worked closely with project managers across the different projects in Deloitte in order to develop efficient interviewing practices and to hire passionate, talented, and knowledgeable developers.

- React
- Redux
- Typescript
- Jest
- Azure
- Webpack
- SCSS

#### Full-Stack Developer at Questia Group October 2015- December 2017

♦ https://questiagroup.com/

Questia Group offers agile market research services offering real time results for a fraction of the cost of 'traditional' methods.

As a Full-Stack Developer at Questia, I have helped build the web / mobile platforms necessary for the business to function. This included the primary platform for users to interact with each other, to view their profiles, answer dynamic surveys, etc. In addition to this, I have also helped build the admin website that allows content managers to create dynamic surveys, manage users, send newsletters, create raffles, post articles, etc.

I have **created a mobile-companion application with similar features** as the primary platform so that users can more easily stay in touch with the surveys and articles posted within the app.

- AngularJS
- Boostrap
- BackboneJS

- PHP Symfony2
- Java Hibernate
- MySQL
- Ionic Cordova

#### PROJECTS (2)

# **Deep Learning Models**

Having fun with understanding and building deep learning models.

- Predictive Neural Networks
- Convoluted Neural Networks for Classification
- Recurrent Neural Networks for generating data / sentiment prediction
- Generative Adversarial Networks for generating pictures, such as human faces

#### Crypto

Building a NodeJS Binance trading bot that detects volatility spikes and attempts to profit off of them.

#### EDUCATION (1) —

**Bachelors Cybernetics & Software Development** at Academia de Studii Economice București **2017 - 2014** 

#### **REFERENCES**

" Contact personally for feedback."

# Klaus Zöggeler, Leader Digital Development, INNIO GROUP

"It is my pleasure to recommend Dragos Marinescu both as a person and as a professional. I have known Dragos for over two years, during which time he worked as a full-stack software developer in my team. From day one, during the time that he has worked in our company, Dragos impressed us with his willingness to learn and his capacity to understand new concepts. Also, he has a work rate that I have rarely seen at other developers. He has quickly established himself as a reliable programmer, writing good quality code and supporting the team whenever needed. He is both very bright and quite motivated. I am confident that he will quickly become an indispensable asset of any software development team. Dragos often surprised everyone with out-of-the box ideas or solutions to different problems. I particularly appreciate his willingness to take initiative to help the team achieve it's goals and deliver on time."

Horia Andrei Văleanu, CTO, Questia Group.